<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: productivity | Zach Galant]]></title>
  <link href="http://zgalant.github.com/blog/categories/productivity/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zgalant.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-06T19:49:25-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://zgalant.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zach Galant]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Audio Books]]></title>
    <link href="http://zgalant.github.com/blog/2013/03/23/audio-books/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-23T23:35:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://zgalant.github.com/blog/2013/03/23/audio-books</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've decided I will start to listen to audio books. I really don't know why I haven't started doing this before because they really make perfect sense for me. I haven't read books for fun in years, and that's kind of a problem, so here's why audio books are the solution.</p>

<h3>I'm Bad at Reading</h3>

<p>That sounds odd, but I don't mean that I'm not literate. What I really mean is that I am bad at sitting down, opening up a book, starting to read it, and not falling asleep. I'm so confident that I'll be unable to read it while staying awake that I don't even try to read books. Maybe it's attention span, since I'm able to read articles, but something about books just puts me to sleep.</p>

<h3>I Spend a Lot of Time Driving and Traveling</h3>

<p>I hate driving. It's necessary to get places, but it's really boring for me, and I hate wasting the time. Listening to audiobooks in the car is a great solution to making long drives feel productive. Now, if I spend a lot of time driving, at least I'll start to cruise through books. I also spend a lot of time on public transportation and in airports and on airplanes, which are also perfect times to just listen to books and not feel like I've lost the time.</p>

<h3>I can speed them up</h3>

<p>Just like lectures, I can speed up audio books and feel even more productive. 2x speed sounds normal to me, so why not feel twice as productive?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
